Welcome back English
learners. My name is Marco
and I'm joined here by
the lovely Erica and today
we're going to be bringing
you another great lesson.
One of the lessons
that you requested.
Yes, that's right. Actually, Maxim
asked requested this one, right?
I think he's really into
research and investigation.
So we're bringing
you a great lesson
about this topic. Okay,
so I'm really excited to
hear this dialogue
all about research.
So why don't we start
listening to two university
professors discussing
an important question.
We've been over
this a thousand times.
The data is irrefutable. Look,
we've done extensive research,
built studies and read
the literature, and there
is conclusive evidence
to support my theory.
Horowitz, I beg to
differ. Even in your most
recent study, the investigative
approach was flawed.
You know as well
as I do, the collection
of data was not systematic
and there's a large
margin of error to draw
a definitive conclusion
based on that data
would be misleading.
Thought is preposterous.
You are trying to
single handedly solve
one of the world's greatest
mysteries and yet you're oblivious to the
fact that you're wrong or are not wrong.
Look, chicken came first.
No, the egg came first.
Look, chicken, egg, look,
chicken, the egg, look,
chicken, the egg. All
right, so interesting,
which came first, the
chicken or the egg?
It's an age-old question,
isn't it? And apparently
they are not going
to agree anytime soon.
All right, well, what
they can agree about is
this awesome language.
So why don't we take a look
at it now in language
takeaway? Language takeaway.
Okay, on language
takeaway today, we have some
really great words and
this first one is really good.
Irrefutable.
Irrefutable. Irrefutable.
The data is irrefutable.
Okay, so if the
professor says that
the data is irrefutable,
what does he mean
by that? He's saying that
you cannot deny it.
It is really, really true.
It is really true. There
is no way this is a lie.
Exactly. Okay. Irrefutable
evidence, for example.
Yeah, that's a great
phrase. All right, so
the professor complained
that Dr. Harlowitz's
experiment was
flawed. Flawed. Flawed.
So flawed. Is that an
adjective a verb or a noun?
Hmm, it is an adjective here.
Now, when something is flawed,
there is a problem with it, right?
There is a mistake.
An error. Yeah. Okay.
So this adjective is a
way of saying that his
experiment has a
flaw. A mistake. Exactly.
So flawed is the adjective
of a flaw. Right. Okay.
Now, the reason that his
study or his experiment
was flawed is because
it was not systematic.
Systematic. Systematic. So systematic.
That's an interesting word.
Hmm. Now, I think we
can recognize the word
system in here, right?
Right. So when something is
systematic, it
follows a process.
A certain order. Yes,
a certain system. Right.
So that's basically what
systematic means to follow a certain
order to be more organized,
right? Exactly. Yeah.
Okay. And what about our next word?
Proposterous. Proposterous. Proposterous.
That is preposterous.
I love this phrase.
It usually goes together,
right? That is preposterous.
Yeah. Okay. So what does
it mean when I say that?
It means it's absurd.
It's ridiculous.
Right. It doesn't make sense.
I can't believe you said that.
All right. Well, this is a really
interesting phrase. But I think it's a little
bit more common when
it's used by older people.
Yeah. I don't think I don't really see a
young person going up to someone and say,
"Hey, that's preposterous."
Yeah. But it is a wonderful phrase.
Now, our final phrase
for takeaway, oblivious.
Oblivious. You're oblivious to the fact.
So a person that is oblivious to something.
They don't know or they're unaware. Okay.
So they ignore maybe the facts over.
Exactly. They
don't see it. Yeah.
You're oblivious to the
fact that we're in a recession.
Okay. Or he is
completely oblivious.
You can just say it like that,
right? Yep. He doesn't know.
Okay. So we took a look at some of the
great vocabulary we found in the dialogue.
But there were also some really good
phrases that I think we should look at.
Okay. And let's take a look at
those and putting it together.
Putting it together.
You know, Marko,
one of the things I love
about English is the way
that words seem to fit
together, like blocks
coming together.
And here we have a lot of
great examples of these words
that fit together
really nicely. Okay.
So why don't we look at
those? And our first one now is
extensive research, extensive
research, extensive research.
All right. So we
know extensive means
a lot. A lot. Yeah.
So that's really good.
When you put it to get extensive
research, it means you have
a lot of research. You have really studied.
You have really looked things up.
Okay, extensive research.
Another great research
related phrase here
is conclusive evidence.
Conclusive evidence.
All right. Now, the first
word they're conclusive.
When something is conclusive, you can't
argue with that. It's the final decision.
All right. Well, the professor
complained that Horowitz's
that Horowitz's investigative
approach was flawed, right?
So this is our next phrase,
investigative approach.
Investigative approach.
Okay. So I remember the word "investigate"
is a verb. Yes. But in this case,
it's an adjective.
It's an adjective.
When something is
investigative, it's obviously having
to do with an investigation.
So the approach or the,
so when he said "investigateive
approach," just the, I mean,
just simply the way you
investigate. Okay. The problem.
The way he investigated. Okay.
Very interesting. What about this
other phrase that I saw?
It was really interesting.
Definitive conclusion.
So a definitive
conclusion. All right.
Well, again, I think we know
the word conclusion, right?
Okay. So it's a final
judgment or decision.
All right. When
something is definitive,
you can't argue with it or change it. Okay.
So the conclusion or the, the final result
is, is final. Like, there is no way of
arguing it. Exactly. Okay. All right.
Definitive conclusion. This
is some great language.
So why don't we listen
to it one more time
in the dialogue? We've been
over this a thousand times.
The data is irrefutable.
Look, we've done extensive
research, built studies
and read the literature, and there is
conclusive evidence to support my theory.
Coro, it's I beg to differ.
Evening your most recent study,
the investigative
approach was flawed.
You know, as well as I do, the
collection of data was not systematic.
And there's a large
margin of error
to draw a definitive
conclusion based on that data
would be misleading.
Doctors preposterous.
You are trying to
single-handedly solve one of the
world's greatest mysteries.
And yet you're oblivious
to the fact that you're
wrong or are not wrong.
The chicken came first.
No, the egg came first.
The chicken. Egg.
The chicken. The egg.
What's written? The egg.
So an interesting question.
What do you think?
What came first? The
chicken or the egg?
Well, if you ask me, it was the
egg. It was the egg. Yeah. Interesting.
What about why did the chicken
cross the road? To get to the other side.
Do you think that's
really the reason?
Well, there's a million different
reasons, but this is great.
I'm glad you brought that up, because
this is like the classic English joke.
The classic English joke, right?
Why did the chicken cross the
road? And the answer is always,
well, there are a
million answers.
So do you guys know
any chicken jokes? Yeah.
Why don't you come to
our website, Englishpot.com.
And on the comment section, why don't you
leave us your thoughts on what came first?
The chicken or the egg? And
why do you think the chicken
crossed the road? All
right. Well, you really look
forward to hearing your
ideas. And Marco and I
will be around to answer
your questions. So I
think we're out
of time for today.
But thanks for listening. And
we'll see you there. Goodbye.